  [
    
    {
        "id": 1,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "From which language is the word ‘ketchup’ derived?",
        "answer": "Chinese"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 2,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What country has the largest population in Europe?",
        "answer": "Russia"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 3,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Who portrayed Edward Scissorhands?",
        "answer": "Johnny Depp"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 4,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What are made and repaired by a cobbler?",
        "answer": "Shoes"
    },

    {
        "id": 5,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What is an endoscope used to examine?",
        "answer": "The inside of the body"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 6,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Apart from womanizing and producing films, what was the other passion of Howard Hughes?",
        "answer": "Aviation"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 7,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What colour are the four stars on the flag of New Zealand?",
        "answer": "Red"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 8,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "How many states make up the United States of America?",
        "answer": "50"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 9,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which English football team plays its home matches at Old Trafford?",
        "answer": "Manchester United"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 10,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Mr. Carson is the name of the butler in which popular TV costume drama?",
        "answer": "Downton Abbey"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 11,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Comedy duo Ant and Dec are originally from which English city?",
        "answer": "Newcastle upon Tyne"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 12,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In the medical profession, what do the initials ‘GP’ stand for?",
        "answer": "General practitioner"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 13,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which German football team won the Champions League in 2013?",
        "answer": "Bayern Munich"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 14,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Maris Piper and King Edward are varieties of what?",
        "answer": "Potato"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 15,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "H2O is the chemical formula for what?",
        "answer": "Water"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 16,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which English king married six times?",
        "answer": "Henry VIII"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 17,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Whom did David Cameron succeed as the British prime minister?",
        "answer": "Gordon Brown"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 18,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Blandenburg, Bremen and Lower Saxony are states in which European country?",
        "answer": "Germany"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 19,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Complete the title of the play by Shakespeare – ‘The Merchant of …’?",
        "answer": "Venice"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 20,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "By what name is the TV adventurer Edward Michael Grylls more commonly known?",
        "answer": "Bear Grylls"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 21,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which fictional sleuth was played on TV for 25 years by David Suchet?",
        "answer": "Hercule Poirot"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 22,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Brie and Camembert are types of which food?",
        "answer": "Cheese"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 23,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Complete the title of the hit romantic comedy – ‘When Harry Met …’?",
        "answer": "Sally"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 24,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What type of creature lives in an apiary?",
        "answer": "Bee"
    },

    {
        "id": 25,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In London, what can be found at Spitalfields, Portobello Road and Camden?",
        "answer": "Markets"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 26,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which British artist is famous for his spot paintings?",
        "answer": "Damien Hirst"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 27,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "A rugby union team is made up of how many players?",
        "answer": "15"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 28,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which British patron saint is celebrated annually on 1st of March?",
        "answer": "St. David"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 29,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What colour flag is awarded to a beach that meets high standards for cleanliness, safety and water quality?",
        "answer": "Blue"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 30,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Pantomimes traditionally take place at what time of the year?",
        "answer": "Christmas"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 31,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In which religion is Krishna a God?",
        "answer": "Hinduism"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 32,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In which sport are there playing positions called flanker, fly half and tight-head prop?",
        "answer": "Rugby Union"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 33,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What boy’s name is also the capital of the Falkland Islands?",
        "answer": "Stanley"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 34,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "TV comedy ‘Dad’s Army’ was set during which conflict?",
        "answer": "World War 2"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 35,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Stilton, Wensleydale and Yarg are types of which food?",
        "answer": "Cheese"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 36,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In which decade did Queen Elizabeth II become the British monarch?",
        "answer": "1950s"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 37,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In which country was Adolf Hitler born?",
        "answer": "Austria"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 38,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The phrase ‘three strikes and you’re out’ originates from which sport?",
        "answer": "Baseball"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 39,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which English city is often abbreviated to Soton?",
        "answer": "Southampton"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 40,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which mountain range forms a natural border between France and Spain?",
        "answer": "Pyrenees"
    },

    {
        "id": 41,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Shannon Airport is in which European country?",
        "answer": "Ireland"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 42,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Nora Batty was a character in which long-running TV comedy?",
        "answer": "Last of the Summer Wine"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 43,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Murrayfield Stadium is in which British city?",
        "answer": "Edinburgh"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 44,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In which sport may a player score a birdie, eagle or albatross?",
        "answer": "Golf"
    },

    {
        "id": 45,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Goal shooter, goal attack and wing attack are playing positions in which sport?",
        "answer": "Netball"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 46,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The underwater city of Bikini Bottom is the setting for which popular children’s cartoon?",
        "answer": "SpongeBob SquarePants"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 47,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Colombo is the largest city of which Asian country?",
        "answer": "Sri Lanka"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 48,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which sci-fi character has been played on the big screen by Leonard Nimoy and more recently by Zachary Quinto?",
        "answer": "Mr. Spock"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 49,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "How many English monarchs have been called Edward?",
        "answer": "8"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 50,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In Tolkien’s ‘The Hobbit’, what type of fictional creature is Smaug?",
        "answer": "Dragon"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 51,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Carrow Road is the home ground of which English football team?",
        "answer": "Norwich City"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 52,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The ‘Financial Times’ newspaper is printed on what colour paper?",
        "answer": "Pink"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 53,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "For what is ‘the dunny’ an Australian slang term?",
        "answer": "The toilet"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 54,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The Canary Islands are a region of which country?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 55,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In the popular video game series, what type of animal is Sonic?",
        "answer": "Hedgehog"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 56,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Greens, fairways and bunkers are part of the setting for which sport?",
        "answer": "Golf"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 57,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which UK city was the venue for the 2014 Commonwealth Games?",
        "answer": "Glasgow"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 58,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Ramsay Street is the setting for which TV soap?",
        "answer": "Neighbours"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 59,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The Great Barrier Reef lies off the coast of which country?",
        "answer": "Australia"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 60,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which pair of superheroes are known as the ‘Dynamic Duo’?",
        "answer": "Batman and Robin"
    },

    {
        "id": 61,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which Olympic sport takes place in a velodrome?",
        "answer": "Cycling"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 62,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which joint connects the foot to the leg?",
        "answer": "Ankle"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 63,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In London, what are Tate Modern, Tate Britain and White Cube?",
        "answer": "Art galleries"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 64,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What name is shared by a brass musical instrument and a type of ice-cream cone?",
        "answer": "Cornet"
    },

    {
        "id": 65,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Prior to joining the euro, what was the currency of Spain?",
        "answer": "Peseta"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 66,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which American city was also the title of a 2002 Oscar-winning film starring Catherine Zeta-Jones and Richard Gere?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 67,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What item, useful in the rain, provided the title of a hit single of Rihanna?",
        "answer": "Umbrella"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 68,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Aintree racecourse is in which city?",
        "answer": "Liverpool"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 69,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Coniston Water and Derwent Water are part of which UK National Park?",
        "answer": "Lake District"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 70,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Speaker’s Corner is a feature of which London park?",
        "answer": "Hyde Park"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 71,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Harley Street in London is commonly associated with which profession?",
        "answer": "Medicine"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 72,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What is the national flower of Wales?",
        "answer": "Daffodil"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 73,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Ringway airport serves which British city?",
        "answer": "Manchester"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 74,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which fortification stretches from Bowness-on-Solway to Wallsend?",
        "answer": "Hadrian’s Wall"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 75,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "St. Mungo’s Cathedral is in which Scottish city?",
        "answer": "Glasgow"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 76,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Glyndebourne is associated with which type of music?",
        "answer": "Opera"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 77,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The Balti Triangle is an area of which British city?",
        "answer": "Birmingham"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 78,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The Derby is held at which English racecourse?",
        "answer": "Epsom"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 79,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which English county is known as ‘Shakespeare’s County’?",
        "answer": "Warwickshire"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 80,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The Clifton Suspension Bridge spans which river?",
        "answer": "Avon"
    },

    {
        "id": 81,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "By population, what is the largest city in Scotland?",
        "answer": "Glasgow"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 82,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The Soap opera ‘Brookside’ was set in which city?",
        "answer": "Liverpool"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 83,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Freestyle and Greco-Roman are disciplines of which Olympic sport?",
        "answer": "Wrestling"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 84,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Quebec is a province in which Commonwealth country?",
        "answer": "Canada"
    },

    {
        "id": 85,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "R.I. are the initials of which American state?",
        "answer": "Rhode Island"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 86,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "A round of championship golf consists of how many holes?",
        "answer": "18"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 87,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The cricket ground Trent Bridge is in which English city?",
        "answer": "Nottingham"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 88,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The province of Rioja, which gives its name to the famous drink, is in which country?",
        "answer": "Spain"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 89,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Ibrox Stadium and Celtic Park are football grounds in which British city?",
        "answer": "Glasgow"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 90,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The Latin phrase ‘Utrinque Paratus’ is the motto of which regiment of the British Army?",
        "answer": "Parachute Regiment"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 91,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "The guilder was the former currency of which European country?",
        "answer": "Netherlands"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 92,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which of tennis’ four major championships is played on clay?",
        "answer": "French Open"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 93,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "A pug is a breed of which domestic pet?",
        "answer": "Dog"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 94,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which European capital city is known in its native language as Praha?",
        "answer": "Prague"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 95,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What colour beret is worn by members of the Royal Marines?",
        "answer": "Green"
    }, 
    
    {
        "id": 96,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which northern English city was known in Roman times as Deva?",
        "answer": "Chester"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 97,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Calcio is the Italian word for which sport?",
        "answer": "Football"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 98,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "Which outdoor sport is played at Lord’s?",
        "answer": "Cricket"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 99,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "In terms of area, what is the largest country in South America?",
        "answer": "Brazil"
    }, 

    {
        "id": 100,
        "category": "",
        "difficulty": "Easy",
        "question": "What does the ‘MI’ in ‘MI5’ and ‘MI6’ stand for?",
        "answer": "Military Intelligence"
    }
   
 ]

